<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>self-improvement on Eric Khun</title>
    <link>https://erickhun.com/categories/self-improvement/</link>
    <description>Recent content in self-improvement on Eric Khun</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2019 11:16:22 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://erickhun.com/categories/self-improvement/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Why you should have a side project</title>
      <link>https://erickhun.com/posts/why-you-should-have-a-side-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2019 11:16:22 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://erickhun.com/posts/why-you-should-have-a-side-project/</guid>
      <description>I often advocate people surrounding me to build their own side projects. I believe they can fulfill you in so many ways: for your career, your relationships, or your independence. Buffer, the company I currently work for, was itself a side project.
I&amp;rsquo;ve built myself multiple side projects. The major ones being PartyInBeijing (inactive), Nodablock (inactive), Citymayor(need to fix), and now TravelHustlers. I believe each of them contributed and lead me to my current situation: being satisfied in my career, financially, and socially.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I did a Plum.io test</title>
      <link>https://erickhun.com/posts/plum-io-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 17:35:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://erickhun.com/posts/plum-io-test/</guid>
      <description>An ex-classmate shared with me today the Plum.io test. My results are available here.
The 3 &amp;ldquo;talents&amp;rdquo; that stands out were:
 Conflict: Resolution: stay calm , empathie, being polite when you disagree Teamwork: be tactful, courteous of others, be sensitive to others needs, support others, encourage positive interactions Communication: &amp;ldquo;good long term relationships, even with difficult people&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;built on tactful and considerate interactions&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Good at knowing the right thing to say to people and at understanding how people will accept what you are going to say to them&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;soliciting and accepting feedback and criticism from others&amp;rdquo;  Sounds about right?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>