<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Workout on Eric Khun</title>
    <link>https://erickhun.com/tags/workout/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Workout on Eric Khun</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 11:51:22 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://erickhun.com/tags/workout/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>fitness is the first step to greatness</title>
      <link>https://erickhun.com/post/fitness-is-the-first-step-to-greatness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 11:51:22 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://erickhun.com/post/fitness-is-the-first-step-to-greatness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fitness is the first step to greatness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is my favorite quote that &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/justinkan&#34;&gt;Justin Kan&lt;/a&gt; keep saying in Snapchat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a quote I just start understand. I start working out 1 year ago. I can definitely relate this to work. and I find I can achieve more at work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;have-clear-goals-to-challenge-yourself&#34;&gt;Have clear goals to challenge yourself&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I started, I tried to exercice every 2-3 days without any goals. Picking a workout machine randonly, and adding weight randomly. I also didn&amp;rsquo;t keep track of how heavy I could lift on each machine. I think at this time I just didn&amp;rsquo;t know what I was doing. My motivation decreased a lot and I noticed that I went less often in the gym.
What is wrong with that? My motivation kept lowering week after week. I went to the gym less often, and started to find many excuse to not go. I start forgetting the benefits of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i2.kym-cdn.com/photos/images/facebook/000/234/765/b7e.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;No idea what I&#39;m doing&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At &lt;a href=&#34;https://buffer.com&#34;&gt;Buffer&lt;/a&gt;, we&amp;rsquo;re lucky to have a slack channel called #improvements-fitness where bufferoos talk about their improvements and everything fitness related. I started to dig into the channel history and found a program that was quoted many times: &lt;a href=&#34;http://stronglifts.com&#34;&gt;Stronglift 5x5&lt;/a&gt; . After a quick look , it looked quite simple, and it allows you to progress quickly without having much knowledge!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>