<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>blockchain on Eric Khun</title>
    <link>https://erickhun.com/categories/blockchain/</link>
    <description>Recent content in blockchain on Eric Khun</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 09:08:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://erickhun.com/categories/blockchain/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>DeFi: Make money like a bank</title>
      <link>https://erickhun.com/posts/defi-make-money-like-a-bank/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 09:08:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://erickhun.com/posts/defi-make-money-like-a-bank/</guid>
      <description>DeFi, or Decentralized Finance, is probably one of today&amp;rsquo;s biggest opportunities to generate interest out of your own money. It unlocked the possibility for anyone to become their own bank. DeFi allows its users to make all kinds of various transactions, like exchanging currencies (via your bank that uses the FOREX in the traditional financial system), lending or borrowing. And with this capabilities, comes the possibility to collect fees and interest from those actions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NFT misconception: JPEG aren&#39;t on the Blockchain</title>
      <link>https://erickhun.com/posts/nft-misconception-image-arent-on-blockchains/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Oct 2021 13:08:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://erickhun.com/posts/nft-misconception-image-arent-on-blockchains/</guid>
      <description>Today&amp;rsquo;s biggest misconception about NFTs is that they&amp;rsquo;re &amp;ldquo;jpeg&amp;rdquo; images stored on the Ethereum blockchain, it&amp;rsquo;s not. Probably because that digital art can be easy to visualize, and famous artists attempt today to sell their digital art as an NFT on a platform such as Opensea, it has gained lot of attention these past months.
Artists start creating them on a piece of paper, then their computer. But when they convert it to an NFT, what makes you the owner of it?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When code is law</title>
      <link>https://erickhun.com/posts/when-code-is-law/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 09:16:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://erickhun.com/posts/when-code-is-law/</guid>
      <description>How can you trust an individual, company, or government with the money you send to them? What tells you there are no hidden fees, or middleman in the contract you’re signing for? How do you make sure terms won’t be changed? Those are one of the exciting things I’m excited about smart contracts on public blockchains, the “Code is Law” feature (also called “immutability”). They are the promises of what a smart contract can fulfill.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Explaining blockchains to developers</title>
      <link>https://erickhun.com/posts/explaining-blockchains-to-developers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 09:23:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://erickhun.com/posts/explaining-blockchains-to-developers/</guid>
      <description>What is a blockchain? Why are some people using it? Even as a developer, it took me a few years to understand what a blockchain really is,how it is working from inside out. I&amp;rsquo;ll share here what I believe is a comprehensive explanation of what is a blockchain from a developer point of view.
What is a blockchain? In simple words, it’s a slow database.
For Bitcoin, this database contains a ledger only.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup your Ethereum node with geth on the Ropsten test network</title>
      <link>https://erickhun.com/posts/setup-your-ethereum-node-geth-ropsten-test-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2018 11:16:22 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://erickhun.com/posts/setup-your-ethereum-node-geth-ropsten-test-network/</guid>
      <description>This is a step by step guide to setup your own Ethereum node on the Ropsten network. At the end of this guide you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to:
 Run your own ethereum node synced with the Ropsten testnet network Making sure to keep the node in sync with the blockchain on the network Be able to communicate via the JSON-RPC API of your own node Using the same method to run your node on the main network  Why do you want run your own node?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
