<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Eric Khun</title>
    <link>https://erickhun.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Eric Khun</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2018 11:16:22 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://erickhun.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup you own Etheureum node with geth on the Ropsten test network</title>
      <link>https://erickhun.com/post/setup-your-own-ethereum-node-for-ropsten/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2018 11:16:22 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://erickhun.com/post/setup-your-own-ethereum-node-for-ropsten/</guid>
      <description>You&amp;rsquo;re on the right place for a step by step guide to setup your own Ethereum node on the Ropsten. At the end of this guide you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to:
 Run your own ethereum node Making sure to keep your node in sync with your chosen network Be able to communicate via the json rpc API of your node  Why ?  Once your dAPP and Smart Contract are working locally, you&amp;rsquo;ll want to test it on a real network with (almost) real condition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I did a Plum.io test</title>
      <link>https://erickhun.com/post/plum-io-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 17:35:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://erickhun.com/post/plum-io-test/</guid>
      <description>An ex-classmate asked me today to do a Plum.io. I was expecting a coding/algo/logic test. But it was mostly some soft skills questions with a small part of logic.
My results are available here. I&amp;rsquo;m a the top 5% to Conflict Resolution, Teamwork, and Communication. I&amp;rsquo;m not totally sure what means the top 5%, and really curious about my score on the other categories.
What&amp;rsquo;s also interesting, is that I did the test a second time, and got a lower score.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>fitness is the first step to greatness</title>
      <link>https://erickhun.com/post/fitness-is-the-first-step-to-greatness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 11:51:22 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://erickhun.com/post/fitness-is-the-first-step-to-greatness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fitness is the first step to greatness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is my favorite quote that &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/justinkan&#34;&gt;Justin Kan&lt;/a&gt; keep saying in Snapchat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a quote I just start understand. I start working out 1 year ago. I can definitely relate this to work. and I find I can achieve more at work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;have-clear-goals-to-challenge-yourself&#34;&gt;Have clear goals to challenge yourself&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I started, I tried to exercice every 2-3 days without any goals. Picking a workout machine randonly, and adding weight randomly. I also didn&amp;rsquo;t keep track of how heavy I could lift on each machine. I think at this time I just didn&amp;rsquo;t know what I was doing. My motivation decreased a lot and I noticed that I went less often in the gym.
What is wrong with that? My motivation kept lowering week after week. I went to the gym less often, and started to find many excuse to not go. I start forgetting the benefits of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i2.kym-cdn.com/photos/images/facebook/000/234/765/b7e.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;No idea what I&#39;m doing&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At &lt;a href=&#34;https://buffer.com&#34;&gt;Buffer&lt;/a&gt;, we&amp;rsquo;re lucky to have a slack channel called #improvements-fitness where bufferoos talk about their improvements and everything fitness related. I started to dig into the channel history and found a program that was quoted many times: &lt;a href=&#34;http://stronglifts.com&#34;&gt;Stronglift 5x5&lt;/a&gt; . After a quick look , it looked quite simple, and it allows you to progress quickly without having much knowledge!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hi, I&#39;m Eric :)</title>
      <link>https://erickhun.com/post/hi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 02:00:06 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://erickhun.com/post/hi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi there, thanks for passing by! I&amp;rsquo;m Eric, engineer at &lt;a href=&#34;https://buffer.com&#34;&gt;Buffer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember writting a blog in French few years ago in high school. I&amp;rsquo;m not really sure what it was about, certainly about technology and me being intrigued about internet. For some reasons, I stopped writting, but always wanted to get back at it&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So Why?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>