<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Eric Khun</title>
    <link>https://erickhun.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Eric Khun</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2019 11:16:22 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://erickhun.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Why you should have a side project</title>
      <link>https://erickhun.com/posts/why-you-should-have-a-side-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2019 11:16:22 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://erickhun.com/posts/why-you-should-have-a-side-project/</guid>
      <description>I often advocate people surrounding me to build their own side projects. I believe they can fulfill you in so many ways: for your career, your relationships, or your independence. Buffer, the company I currently work for, was itself a side project.
I&amp;rsquo;ve built myself multiple side projects. The major ones being PartyInBeijing (inactive), Nodablock (inactive), Citymayor(need to fix), and now TravelHustlers. I believe each of them contributed and lead me to my current situation: being satisfied in my career, financially, and socially.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I kept working out while traveling for 4 years? 🏋️‍♀️ 🏐 🌍</title>
      <link>https://erickhun.com/posts/traveling-and-working-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 20:18:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://erickhun.com/posts/traveling-and-working-out/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been flying between a lot between countries this past 4 years. Many people ask me how I keep exercising while moving between countries that often. I&amp;rsquo;ll try to explain here what I think helped me to keep that consistency.
For a bit of background, I&amp;rsquo;ve always enjoyed playing volleyball since middle school, and try to go at least once a week, in any country I visited. It was already a habit I had since I was younger and I believe it helped me a lot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup your Ethereum node with geth on the Ropsten test network</title>
      <link>https://erickhun.com/posts/setup-your-ethereum-node-geth-ropsten-test-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2018 11:16:22 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://erickhun.com/posts/setup-your-ethereum-node-geth-ropsten-test-network/</guid>
      <description>This is a step by step guide to setup your own Ethereum node on the Ropsten network. At the end of this guide you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to:
 Run your own ethereum node synced with the Ropsten testnet network Making sure to keep the node in sync with the blockchain on the network Be able to communicate via the JSON-RPC API of your own node Using the same method to run your node on the main network  Why do you want run your own node?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fitness is the first step to greatness</title>
      <link>https://erickhun.com/posts/fitness-is-the-first-step-to-greatness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 11:51:22 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://erickhun.com/posts/fitness-is-the-first-step-to-greatness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fitness is the first step to greatness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is my favorite quote that &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/justinkan&#34;&gt;Justin Kan&lt;/a&gt; keep saying in Snapchat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a quote I just start understand. I start working out 1 year ago. I can definitely relate this to work. and I find I can achieve more at work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;have-clear-goals-to-challenge-yourself&#34;&gt;Have clear goals to challenge yourself&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I started, I tried to exercice every 2-3 days without any goals. Picking a workout machine randonly, and adding weight randomly. I also didn&amp;rsquo;t keep track of how heavy I could lift on each machine. I think at this time I just didn&amp;rsquo;t know what I was doing. My motivation decreased a lot and I noticed that I went less often in the gym.
What is wrong with that? My motivation kept lowering week after week. I went to the gym less often, and started to find many excuse to not go. I start forgetting the benefits of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i2.kym-cdn.com/photos/images/facebook/000/234/765/b7e.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;No idea what I&#39;m doing&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At &lt;a href=&#34;https://buffer.com&#34;&gt;Buffer&lt;/a&gt;, we&amp;rsquo;re lucky to have a slack channel called #improvements-fitness where bufferoos talk about their improvements and everything fitness related. I started to dig into the channel history and found a program that was quoted many times: &lt;a href=&#34;http://stronglifts.com&#34;&gt;Stronglift 5x5&lt;/a&gt; . After a quick look&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hi, I&#39;m Eric :)</title>
      <link>https://erickhun.com/posts/hi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 02:00:06 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://erickhun.com/posts/hi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi there, thanks for passing by! I&amp;rsquo;m Eric, engineer at &lt;a href=&#34;https://buffer.com&#34;&gt;Buffer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember writting a blog in French few years ago in high school. I&amp;rsquo;m not really sure what it was about, certainly about technology and me being intrigued about internet. For some reasons, I stopped writting, but always wanted to get back at it&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So Why?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>